A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Biographical Works, ca. 1952-1960; 5; 9 Document Box(es)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 22 (Box 57, Folder 499)
    Anti-Saloon League Rockefeller Boards Rockefeller Center World Wars I and II Variety and Extent of Philanthropic Contributions Business Responsibilities
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 23 (Box 57, Folder 500)
    Man Himself Homes Family General Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Children Sources
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 24 (Box 57, Folder 501)
    Sources (continued) Bread Box Files and Laura Spelman Rockefeller Notebooks Travel Itineraries and Reading Notes Account Books, 1887-1900
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 25 (Box 57, Folder 502)
    Speeches Correspondence with Mother, 1891-1914 Correspondence with Mother, 1907-1915 M. Pendo interviews and research trips Fosdick conversations with other than John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 26 (Box 57, Folder 503)
    Fosdick conversations with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 27 (Box 58, Folder 504)
    Letter Books Nevins Books
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 28 (Box 58, Folder 505)
    Scrapbooks
    See also Subseries 7.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 29 (Box 58, Folder 506)
    M. Pendo Research Reports Early Life, original typescript, edited by Raymond B. Fosdick College Years (copy)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 30 (Box 58, Folder 507)
    M. Pendo Research Reports (continued) Courtship Colorado Strike Religion
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 31 (Box 58, Folder 508)
    M. Pendo Research Reports (continued) Father and Son Parks Art Restoration
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Miscellaneous Papers, 1952-1956 (Box 59, Folder 509)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Newspapers Used by Fosdick (Linen-Covered), 1881, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 510)
    "New York Daily Graphic," October 12, 1891 "Evening News, Providence, Rhode Island," n.d.
    This folder is cross-reference to a large portfolio, located in Room 105, Unit 34, Shelf 4.
    See separate package.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Reader Correspondence (A-F), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 511)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Reader Correspondence (G-L), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 512)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Reader Correspondence (M-R), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 513)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Reader Correspondence (S-Z), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 514)
  - Newhall, Nancy - "A Contribution to the Heritage of Every American" (1957) - Letters and Clippings (Box 59, Folder 515)
  - Ross, T. J. - Biographical Sketches, 1949, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 516)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd cooperates with T. J. Ross in keeping biography up to date. Annual corrections of gift list. Biography revised, 1949. Sketch used in 1960. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, T. J. Ross, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler.
  - Tilden, Freeman - "Friend of Our Heritage" - Manuscript Typescript (Box 60, Folder 517)
  - Tilden, Freeman - "Friend of Our Heritage" - Manuscript Typescript - Part 1 (Box 60, Folder 518)
  - Tilden, Freeman - "Friend of Our Heritage" - Manuscript Typescript - Part 2 (Box 60, Folder 519)
  - Tilden, Freeman - "Friend of Our Heritage" - Correspondence with Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1954, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 520)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Rare Books, 1654, 1678, 1723, 1782, 1910, undated; 6; 8 Bound Volumes
  Subseries 6, Rare Books, is arranged in two sections: "Presentation Volumes" and "Works by or about Spelman Family".
  Subseries 6, Rare Books, contains works presented to JDR, Jr. by his mother or by dignitaries. Of special interest is the original bound manuscript of "Aspilogia" (n.d.), a work on ancient warfare, heraldry, and other subjects by Sir Henry Spelman (1564-1641), a historian, Member of Parliament, and ancestor of Laura Spelman Rockefeller. Also present is the first printed edition of that work (London, 1654), which contains copper plate engravings and the only known portrait of John Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury.
  - Presentation Volumes - D'Auberteuil, M. Hilliard. "Essais Historiques et Politiques sur les Anglo-Americains. Tome Premier, Premiere Partie." (Brussels, 1782) (Box 61, Folder 521)
    Presentation copy, signed by Senator Andre Honnerat, December 25, 1936.
  - Presentation Volumes - D'Auberteuil, M. Hilliard. "Essais Historiques et Politiques sur la Revolution de L'Amerique Septentrionale. Tome Second, Premiere Partie." (Brussels, 1782) (Box 61, Folder 522)
    Presentation copy, companion volume.
  - Presentation Volumes - Donnet, Fernand. "Coup d'Oeil sur L'Histoire Financiere D'Anvers" (Anvers, 1926?) Facsimile edition, number 940 of 1050. (Box 62, Folder 523)
    Presentation copy from Elizabeth, Queen of the Belgians, 1928.
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Barbour, Fannie Cooley Williams. "Spelman Genealogy: The English Ancestry and American Descendants of Richard Spelman of Middletown, Connecticut 1700" (New York, 1910) (Box 63, Folder 524)
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Spelman, Sir Henry. "Aspilogia," Original Manuscript, Bound, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 525)
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Uptoni, Nicolai. "De Studio Militari;" De Bado Aureo, Johan. "Tractatus de Armis;" Spelmanni, Henrici. "Aspilogia" (London, 1654) First printed edition. (Box 64, Folder 526)
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Spelman, Henry. "The English Works of Sir Henry Spelman, Kt." (London, 1723) (Box 65, Folder 527)
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Spelman, John. "Aelfredi Magni, Anglorum Regis..." (Oxford, 1678) (Box 065A, Folder 0527A)
  - Works by or about the Spelman Family - Spelman, John. "Aelfredi Magni, Anglorum Regis..." (Oxford, 1678) (Box 065A, Folder 0527A)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Speeches, 1891-1958, n.d.; 8; 8 Document Box(es)
  The material in this subseries is arranged chronologically.
  John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became well known for his Bible class lessons. Speeches demonstrate his theological classes first took place (1894) at the YMCA when JDR Jr. was a student at Brown University. After graduation from Brown, JDR Jr. became affiliated with his father at 26 Broadway, New York City. He participated actively as a member of the Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, and there, for a period of 10 years, conducted a Young Man's Bible Class. A number of these Bible class lessons are included in the speech file. A majority of the speeches he delivered throughout his life echo the religious themes he developed during his years as a Bible class teacher.
  JDR Jr. gradually eased out of much of the family business and turned his attention and dedication to philanthropic endeavors. The speech file richly reveals the causes JDR Jr. espoused. His keen interest in the arts prompted such undertakings as the erection of The Cloisters and Rockefeller Center. Rockefeller contributions, under the direction of JDR Jr., formed the basis for the restoration projects of Williamsburg, Virginia, and several historic properties in Westchester County, New York. JDR Jr.'s interest in historical preservation extended beyond the United States. He became deeply involved in the restoration projects of the Palace of Versailles, Fontainebleau, and the cathedral of Rheims.
  JDR Jr. was a key supporter, during both world wars, of service organizations that would benefit and build morale among the United States servicemen. A number of speeches reflect this interest.
  As chairman of the General Education Board and the International Education Board, education was a prime source of interest to JDR Jr. He sought the betterment of men and women through education both in the United States and abroad. Most prominent in the speech subseries is JDR Jr.'s work on behalf of the United Negro College Fund Campaign and the establishment of the Peking Union Medical College.
  John D. Rockefeller, Jr. firmly believed in promoting greater understanding between labor and capital. He, with the able guidance of Mackenzie King, sought to establish workable partnerships between labor and capital. The speech file contains many of the speeches he delivered on this subject.
  Each speech is assigned to one of the following 10 subject areas: Brotherhood, Education, Fund, Labor, Personal, Religion, Restoration, Social Welfare, Stewardship, Tribute.
  Subject areas were assigned by the General Files staff and the processing archivist.
  Other information in each entry includes: Title (assigned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.), Institution (or group to whom the speech was given), Occasion (reason for the speech), Place (geographic location), Format (includes handwritten outline, typed, magazine article, printed pamphlet).
  - The Kernel of Christianity, November 16, 1891 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    Occasion: Young People's Meeting Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - List of Talks - Extracts of Certain Speeches (Box 71, Folder 0001A)
  - Stumbling Blocks, 1892 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Then Said Jesus, March 18, 1894 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    Institution: Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Place: Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - In My Father's House, April 28, 1895 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Seek Ye First the Kingdom of God, May 12, 1895 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - The Mystery of Evil, n.d., ca. 1900 (Box 71, Folder 0005A)
    Notes found in Fiske, John. "Through Nature to God." (New York: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1899).
    See John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Books.
  - Seek the Best Things, February 4, 1901 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    Institution: Student's Club, No. 129 Lexington Avenue Occasion: Student's Club Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Bible Study for Businessmen, March 21, 1901 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    Institution: Washington Street Baptist Church Occasion: Cooper Class Banquet Place: Lynn, Massachusetts Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Christianity in Business, February 5, 1902 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    Institution: Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Place: Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - Giving, 1904 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    Institution: Fifth Avenue Baptist Church Occasion: Young Men's Bible Class Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Duty, January 1904 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Influence of Example, January 17, 1904 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Need of Christian Work Among the Students of New York City, February 1904 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    Institution: Student's Club, No. 129 Lexington Avenue Occasion: Student's Club reception Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Typed
  - Almost Thou Persuadest Me, March 1904 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Freedom of Salvation, March 1904 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Christian Manhood and How to Attain It, March 27, 1904 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Parable of the Tares, October 23, 1904 (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Parable of the Hidden Treasure, November 1904 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Need of Friendship, February 1906 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    Occasion: Young People's Society Meeting Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Opportunity, January 15, 1907 (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - High Standards, February 18, 1908 (Box 71, Folder 20)
  - Holy Spirit in Paul's Life, December 13, 1908 (Box 71, Folder 21)
  - Rambling Thoughts of a Fellow Worker, February 9, 1909 (Box 71, Folder 22)
    Institution: First Baptist Church Occasion: 17th Annual Dinner of Hubbell's Class Place: Rochester, New York Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Lukewarmness, March 16, 1909 (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - Should a Man Be a Christian?, March 21, 1909 (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - Parables, October 3, 1909 (Box 71, Folder 25)
  - White Slave Traffic, June 29, 1910 (Box 71, Folder 26)
    Institution: County of New York Occasion: Court of General Sessions in and for the Court of New York Place: New York City Subject: Social Welfare Format: Printed
  - A Backward Glance and a Forward Look, January 11, 1911 (Box 71, Folder 27)
  - The Critical Spirit, January 24, 1911 (Box 71, Folder 28)
  - Liberty or Science, November 5, 1911 (Box 71, Folder 29)
  - Police Force from a Citizen's Point of View, February 22, 1912 (Box 71, Folder 30)
    Institution: New York City Police Lieutenant's Association Occasion: Police Lieutenant's Benevolent Association Dinner Place: Waldorf Astoria Hotel, New York City Subject: Stewardship Format: Typed
  - The Young Man's Question: Lord What Would You Have Me Do?, October 7, 1912 (Box 71, Folder 31)
  - Parable of the Pearl, December 9, 1912 (Box 71, Folder 32)
  - Wanted - Power, February 16, 1913 (Box 71, Folder 33)
  - A Dead Weight or a Live Wire, May 11, 1913 (Box 71, Folder 34)
  - Fixing Life's Standards, September 28, 1913 (Box 71, Folder 35)
    Institution: Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Place: Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island Subject: Stewardship Format: Handwritten
  - The Young Man's Religion - a Creed Or a Life?, October 5, 1913 (Box 71, Folder 36)
  - Fixing Life's Standards, January 17, 1914 (Box 71, Folder 37)
  - A Work-a-Day Religion, April 19, 1914 (Box 71, Folder 38)
    Institution: Pocantico Lyceum Occasion: Pocantico Lyceum Vesper Services Place: Pocantico Hills, Tarrytown, New York Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Receiving An Honorary Degree, November 1914 (Box 71, Folder 39)
    Institution: Brown University Occasion: 150th Anniversary of Brown University Place: Providence, Rhode Island Subject: Personal Format: Printed
  - Statement Before U. S. Commission on Industrial Relations, January 25, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 40)
    Institution: U. S. Commission on Industrial Relations Place: Washington, D.C. Subject: Labor Format: Printed
  - The Courage to Be Different, August 2, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 41)
    Institution: Union Church Occasion: Sunset Service Place: Northeast Harbor, Maine Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - Four Parties of a Corporation or Company, September 25 and October 2, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 42)
    Institution: Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Occasion: Joint Meeting of the Officers/Representatives of Employees of Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Place: Pueblo and Denver, Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Handwritten/Printed
  - Service to Our Soldiers and Sailors, October 1915 (Box 71, Folder 43)
    Institution: United War Work Campaign Place: 680 Fifth Avenue, New York City Subject: Fund Format: Printed
  - Labor and Industry, October 8, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 44)
    Institution: Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Occasion: Joint Meeting of Employees of Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Place: Albany Hotel, Pueblo, Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Handwritten/Printed
  - Representation in Industry, December 5, 1919 (Box 71, Folder 45)
    Place: Atlantic City, New Jersey Subject: Labor Format: Typed
  - Service, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 46)
  - Labor and Capital - Partners, January 1916 (Box 71, Folder 47)
    Institution: Atlantic Monthly Mazazine Subject: Labor Format: Magazine article
  - What Place Has Jesus Christ in My Life?, April 2 and 16, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 48)
  - Spiritual Forces Creating and Solving Modern Industrial Problems, May 15, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 49)
    Institution: Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Occasion: Industrial Conference of YMCA Place: Grace Episcopal Church, Cleveland, Ohio Subject: Labor Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - Every Man at Work for His Fellowman, May 15, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 50)
  - Problems of Education, June 6, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 51)
    Institution: University of Chicago Occasion: 25th Anniversary of founding of University of Chicago Place: Noyes Hall, Chicago, Illinois Subject: Education Format: Handwritten
  - Service, June 15, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 52)
    Institution: University of Chicago Occasion: 99th Convocation Exercises of University of Chicago Place: Bartlett Gymnasium Subject: Education Format: Handwritten/Printed
  - My Solution for Labor Problems, August 1916 (Box 71, Folder 53)
    Institution: System Magazine Subject: Labor Format: Magazine article
  - The Personal Relation in Industry, January 11, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 54)
    Institution: Cornell University Occasion: Founder's Day, Cornell University Place: Cornell University Subject: Labor Format: Typed/Reprint in The Efficiency Magazine
  - The Man Born Blind, April 1, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 55)
  - About Angels, August 12, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 56)
  - Work-a-Day Religion, August 19, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 57)
    Institution: Union Church Occasion: Sunday Evening Service Place: Northeast Harbor, Maine Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - Billy Sunday Campaign, October 30, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 0057A)
    Occasion: Organizational banquet of citizens of Providence, Rhode Island Place: Providence, Rhode Island Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Nehemiah's Prayer, November 11, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 58)
  - The Kind of Boy I Would Be if I Were a Boy, November 13, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 59)
    Institution: Fifth Avenue Baptist Church Occasion: Father-son banquet Place: New York City Subject: Stewardship Format: Typed
  - You Men in Khaki Stand on a Higher Plane Than We, November 18, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 60)
    Occasion: Address to servicemen at Camp Dix Place: Camp Dix, New Jersey Subject: Tribute Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - Cooperation, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 61)
    Institution: United War Work Campaign Occasion: Opening of United War Work Campaign Place: New York Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Bible Study for Men, January 29, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 62)
    Institution: Fifth Avenue Baptist Church Occasion: Young Men's Bible Class Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Typed/Printed
  - The Christian Church - What of Its Future, February 9, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 63)
    Institution: Saturday Evening Post Place: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten/Magazine article
  - Choosing the Twelve, February 10, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 64)
  - Brotherhood, April 12-13, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 65)
    Institution: Canadian Club Place: Montreal, Canada/Ottawa, Canada Subject: Brotherhood Format: Handwritten/Typed/Printed
  - The Transfiguration, April 21, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 66)
    Institution: Fifth Avenue Baptist Church Occasion: Young Men's Bible Class Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Typed
  - Bible Study, May 7, 1917 (Box 72, Folder 67)
    Institution: North Presbyterian Church Occasion: Billy Sunday Campaign Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Typed
  - Patriotism and Industry, June 4, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 68)
    Institution: Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Occasion: Address to Colorado Fuel & Iron Company employees Place: Pueblo, Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Typed
  - Brotherhood, June 13, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 69)
    Institution: Denver Civic and Commercial Association Occasion: Meeting of Denver businessmen Place: Denver, Colorado Subject: Brotherhood Format: Typed
  - Fourth of July, July 4, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 70)
    Place: Pocantico Lyceum Subject: Social Welfare Format: Typed
  - Brotherhood - Labor and Capital, August 1, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 71)
    Place: Denver, Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Typed
  - Brotherhood, August 10, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 72)
    Place: Chautauqua, New York Subject: Labor Format: Typed
  - Cooperation and Service, September 10, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 73)
    Institution: Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Occasion: YMCA Campaign Place: Mrs. Arthur James residence Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - United War Work Campaign, November 1918 (Box 72, Folder 74)
    Institution: Greater New York United War Work Campaign Occasion: Phonograph record Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - The Greatest Voluntary Altruistic Movement, November 1918 (Box 72, Folder 75)
    Institution: Greater New York United War Work Campaign Subject: Fund Format: Printed
  - Unity, November 3, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 76)
    Institution: United War Work Campaign Occasion: Fund Place: Madison Square Garden, New York City Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Representation in Industry, December 5, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 77)
    Institution: Chamber of Commerce of the United States Occasion: General Session of the War Emergency and Reconstruction Conference Place: Atlantic City, New Jersey Subject: Labor Format: Typed/Printed
  - Brotherhood, April 9, 1919 (Box 72, Folder 78)
    Occasion: Dedication of the Eliza Lucas Hall Place: Charleston, South Carolina Subject: Brotherhood Format: Typed
  - Ideals, August 17, 1919 (Box 72, Folder 79)
  - Representation in Industry, October 16, 1919 (Box 72, Folder 80)
    Institution: National Industrial Conference Place: Washington, D.C. Subject: Labor Format: Printed
  - To A Very Rich Neighbor, December 1919 (Box 72, Folder 81)
    Institution: Atlantic Monthly Subject: Personal Format: Typed/Magazine article
  - Cooperation/Service, January 8, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 82)
    Institution: Columbia University Club Occasion: 50th Anniversary of Columbia University Club, New York City Place: New York City Subject: Social Welfare Format: Handwritten
  - Cooperation (World's Greatest Need), January 8 & 30, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 83)
    Institution: Interchurch World Movement Occasion: Interchurch World Movement Conference/Laymen's Conference Place: Atlantic City, New Jersey and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Subject: Social Welfare Format: Typed
  - Six Hour Day Aid to Satan, January 26, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 84)
    Institution: New York Tribune Place: New York City Subject: Social Welfare Format: Newspaper publication
  - Love, March 7, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 85)
    Institution: Fifth Avenue Baptist Church Occasion: Young Men's Bible Class Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - Introductory Remarks, April 8, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 86)
    Institution: Interchurch World Movement Occasion: Meeting of Interchurch World Movement Place: Gray's Armory, Cleveland, Ohio Subject: Religion Format: Typed
  - Cooperation, April 9 & 13-18, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 87)
    Institution: Interchurch World Movement Occasion: Meeting of Interchurch World Movement Place: Chicago, Illinois; St. Louis, Missouri; Cincinnati, Ohio; Boston, Massachusetts; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; New York City, New York; Buffalo, New York Subject: Social Welfare Format: Typed
  - Cooperation, April 10, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 88)
    Institution: Interchurch World Movement Occasion: Meeting of Interchurch World Movement Place: Minneapolis, Minnesota Subject: Social Welfare Format: Typed
  - A Christmas Message to Young Men, December 19, 1920 (Box 72, Folder 89)
  - Boy Scout Ideals, February 28, 1921 (Box 72, Folder 90)
    Institution: Boy Scouts of America Occasion: Boy Scout Movement dinner Place: Hotel Biltmore, New York City Subject: Stewardship Format: Typed
  - Samson, March 13, 1921 (Box 72, Folder 91)
  - Cooperation in Industry, April 1921 (Box 72, Folder 92)